

# **Tran Manh Hung**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

[ (+84) 0328-491-676 | | manhhungtran2308@gmail.com | manh-hung-portfolio | manhhung-fpt @GitHub | henry-tran @LinkedIn

Current Software Engineer at bigtech company One Mount Groups. 2+ years experience specializing in the frontend and backend development, infrastructure automa- tion. I aim to keep up with trends in frontend design, best practices, tooling, and development to produce the best possible products. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises. I also can communicate in English fluently (IELTS 6.0 - Reading 6.5).

# **Honors & Awards**

2022 1st Prize Technical Challenge Winner - KMS Fresher Bootcamp 2022

2020 Top 5 English FPT's speaking contests

Ho Chi Minh City Ho Chi Minh City

Oct. 2019 - Apr. 2023

## Education

FPT University Ho Chi Minh City

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Got a 30% FPT's Scholarship.

MMU University

Malaysia

Certificate. IN LEADING PROGRAM

Jan. 2020 - Feb. 2020

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

One Mount Ho Chi Minh City

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (5 months-current)

May. 2023 - Present

- Working according to Agile process, **CRM** Internal management provided the engineering of a microservice web application for spending, invoices, big data of customers, using charts and statistics to plan, market research direction for the company.
- Designed and implemented scalable APIs and background workers with Design-first approach for the project using Front-end such as ReactJs, Next13, Typescript, TailwindCss, Zustand, etc.
   Back-end with C#, .Net MVC.
- Professionally collaborate with other engineers to identify and reduce the number of bugs through unit tests and integration help in the user interface, CI/CD implementation with **Docker**, **Jenkins** pipeline. Task management with **Jira**, **Notion**.
- Design UI/UX interfaces from scratch files using Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator.

#### Madarin Learning Labs. Co., Ltd.

Ho Chi Minh City

FRONT END DEVELOPER (8 months)

Oct. 2022 - May. 2023

- Implementing and designing enterprise-level micro-service applications of Element Management System with latest technologies of Front-end with ReactJs, Typescript, NextJs, The Graph, Chart.js, .NET 6 (MVC), NodeJs, MongoDB, TailwindCSS, Docker, AWS EC2. Back-end with .Net core, C#.
- Provide a system for managing, processing and trading online courses, provide include Web3 Network Layer (EVM Blockchains Etherium), Presentation Layer (Ether.js), Defi (Uniswap), Indentify & Authentication (Metamask), Data (The Graph).
- Implemented several API microservices in the serverless AWS Lambda functions.
- Producing daily **Agile** progress and milestone updates directly to US customers with feature specification and designs for heavy exchanging data workload between devices, **REST API** server and user interface.
- Improving code quality with pull requests, code reviews, unit/integration testing as well as debugging and fixing defects.
- Proficient in Git flow, Gitlabs, Devops with Docker Image, Compose, Jenkins pipeline. Task management with Jira, UI/UX interfaces
  from scratch files using Figma.

#### Nha Nam Publishing and Communications JSC

Ho Chi Minh City

1

BUSINESS STARTUP project (Link Demo: <a href="https://boek.live/">https://boek.live/</a>) (5 months)

Oct. 2022 - Feb. 2023

- A book fair platform called Boek in Viet Nam. Book readers can get the information of book fairs conveniently. This also means that book fairs should be divided into different formats such as online and offline. Moreover, the platform should categorize the genres of book so that it can manage the genre of book. This helps to filter book fairs or book based on book readers' favorite genre. In addition, there are commissions for each genre of book fair. To manage book fair's participants, the administrators shall invite issuers to book fairs and check issuer requests. Book readers can make shipping orders or pick-up orders when viewing the book fairs on this platform.
- Build an Book Fair Management Platform to check input and face data, perform graph tracking and performance using frontend JavaScript library such as ReactJs, Next13, Typescript, TailwindCss, Zustand, etc.
- Design UI/UX interfaces from scratch files using Figma, Draw.io.

KMS Healthcare.Inc Ho Chi Minh City

FRONT END DEVELOPER (3 months)

Jun. 2022 - Aug. 2022

- Build an Al-based platform to check input and face data, perform graph tracking and performance using ReactJs, Redux, Sass, ChartJs and MongoDB.
- Design UI/UX interfaces from scratch files using Figma, Adobe Photoshop
- Included in the development of several products E2E from identifying system requirements and dependencies to workload balancing, software implementation, engineering, testing.
- · Worked directly with product admin to improve user's experience, define and fix software issues.

FPT Software Ho Chi Minh City

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN (6 months)

Dec. 2021 - May. 2022

- Provided the engineering of a microservice web application for users to manage profiles, subscriptions, and billing in terms of software deployment from scratch, which has been accepted for funding of FPT and is still growing fast.
- Designed and implemented scalable APIs and background workers with Design-first approach for the project using Back-end with Java, ASP .NET, SQL Server as database.
   Front-end such as ReactJs.

# **Project**

### Next13-VideoChatAppRealTime

Ho Chi Minh City

LiveDemo: https://next13-chat-app.vercel.app/

- Real-Time Messenger Clone: Next.js 13, React, Tailwind, Prisma, MongoDB, NextAuth, Pusher Key Features:
- · Real-time messaging using Pusher
- · Message notifications and alerts
- · Tailwind design for sleek UI
- VideoCall with Daily.co WebRTC
- · Tailwind animations and transition effects
- · Full responsiveness for all devices
- · Credential authentication with NextAuth
- Google authentication integration
- · Github authentication integration
- · File and image upload using Cloudinary CDN
- · Client form validation and handling using react-hook-form
- · Server error handling with react-toast
- Message read receipts
- · Online/offline user status
- · Group chats and one-on-one messaging
- · Message attachments and file sharing
- User profile customization and settings
- How to write POST, GET, and DELETE routes in route handlers (app/api)
- · How to fetch data in server React components by directly accessing the database (WITHOUT API! like Magic!)
- · Handling relations between Server and Child components in a real-time environment
- · Creating and managing chat rooms and channels